Guide to the Dale R. Corson papers, 1935-2002.
Corson, Dale R. papers, 1963-2002.
- Series V. National and international activities and interests
  - Other national activities and interests
    - Federation of American Scientists, 1947-1951 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Consulting Work for General Electric, 1952-1958 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Government Travel, 1952-1959 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Technological Advisory Panel on Atomic Energy (Defense Dept.), 1953-1956 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - NACA Special Committee on Space Technology, 1957-1958 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics, 1958 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - NASA Photographs, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1966-1979 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - South America (General), 1967-1968 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Danforth Foundation Giant - England/Africa, June 13-July 28, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Danforth Foundation Giant - G01 8702 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Physicians for the Future: Report of the Macy Commission, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Fermiab -URA, 1977-1979 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Robert R. Wilson - Batavia, Illinois, Apr. 27, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Graciela Arabaolasa and Juan Alonso, 1980-1981 (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Scowcroft Commission, 1981-1988 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Cooperation for International Development, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - White Burkett Miller Center, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - White Burkett Miller Center, 1988-1993 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - National Science Foundation - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - MacArthur Foundation - National Institute for the Environment, 1990's (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - WRC Committee on Environment Research, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - Nobel Prize of Engineering - Noyce and Kilby, 1992 (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Reinventing the Research University, June 22-23, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Sigma Xi Forum, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Engineering Academy of Japan: List of Members and Foreign Associates, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 40)
- Series VI. Hobbies and avocations
  - Africa Eclipse, Photos by Corson, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 41-42)
  - Africa, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 43)
  - Life Space Tour, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 44)
  - Life Space Tour, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Photography (Hobby) (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - CAU Photography Course Lecture Notes, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Johnson Art Museum Exhibit, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Photography Exhibit - International Center of Photography, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Photography and Photographs (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Foucault Pendulum (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Sundial (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Sundial - Misc. Correspondence, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Ravnitzky - Suggestions for Sundial, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Sundial - Misc. Correspondence, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Sundial - Misc. Correspondence, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 13-14)
  - Sundial - Misc. Correspondence, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Sundial - Misc. Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Sundial - Equation of Time (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Sundial Story - Alumni News (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - "A Sundial for the Quad." Engineering Cornell Quarterly, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Sundial - Equation of the Graph (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - "The Joseph N. Pew, Jr. Sundial," by Dale R. Corson (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Visit by Messrs. Dunlop and Smith to Cornell to Inspect Sundial (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Sundial - A Simplified Approach to Feedback Control System Design (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Sundial Account E50 8175 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Sundial (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Sundial - Misc. Photographs (Box 37, Folder 26)
- Series VII. Community activities
  - Kendal at Ithaca
    - Kendal Advisory Committee (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Advisory Committee Visit, Apr. 7, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Advisory Committee Visit, May 12, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, June 3, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 30)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, July 7, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 31)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Oct. 6, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 32)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Nov. 4, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 33)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Jan. 12, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 34)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes, Mar. 2, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Apr. 7, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - Advisory Committee Agenda, May 6, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Dec. 1, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 38)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Apr. 4, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 39)
    - Advisory Committee Minutes and Agenda, Nov. 19, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - Annual Meeting, June 1, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 41)
    - Kendal Appraisal Report (Box 37, Folder 42)
    - All Committees Gathering (Box 37, Folder 43)
    - Kendal Board Manual (Box 37, Folder 44)
    - CCRC Committee Minutes and Agenda, Jan. 6-7, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 45)
    - CCRC Committee Minutes and Agenda, Dec. 9-10, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 46)
    - CCRC Committee Minutes and Agenda, Oct. 28-29, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 47)
    - CCRC Committee Minutes and Agenda, Sept. 19-20, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - CCRC Committee Minutes and Agenda, June 19-20, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 49)
    - Cornell Board Minutes and Agenda, Mar. 3-5, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - Kendal Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 51)
    - Kendal Correspondence, 1993 (Box 37, Folder 52-58)
    - Kendal Correspondence, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 59-63)
    - Lloyd Lewis Correspondence, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 64)
    - Kendal Correspondence, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 65-67)
    - Kendal Correspondence, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 68)
    - Kendal Correspondence, 1995 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
    - Kendal Correspondence, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
    - Kendal Correspondence Replies (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Impact Statement (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Groundbreaking, June 30, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Informational (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Marketing and Financial Planning, 1992 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Misc. (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Misc., 1992 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Misc., 1996 (Box 38, Folder 14-15)
    - Misc., 1997 (Box 38, Folder 16-17)
    - Board Meeting - Jan. 15, Feb. 12, Mar. 12, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Philanthropic Fund, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Philanthropy Committee (Box 38, Folder 20-21)
    - Philanthropy Committee, 1996 (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Philanthropy Committee, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Philanthropy Committee, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Pooled Income Fund, Feb. 12, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Property Tax, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Publicity (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Schematic Design Report, Reapplication Concept Plan (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Seminar - Old Wine, New Flasks (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Seminars, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Board of Trustees, July 14, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, Aug. 10, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, Sept. 6, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Marketing Committee, Sept. 16, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Board of Trustees, Sept. 22, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Board of Trustees, Oct. 12, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Board of Trustees Meeting, Nov. 18, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 37)
    - Board of Trustees, Dec. 7, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 38)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, Jan. 27, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 39)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, Feb. 16, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 40)
    - Board of Trustees, Mar. 8, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 41)
    - Board of Trustees, Apr. 12, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 42)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, May 12, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 43)
    - Board Meeting,Westchester, PA, May 25, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 44)
    - Board of Trustees, June 17, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 45)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, Feb. 14, June 3, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 46)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, Apr. 20, Oct. 8, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 47)
    - Board Agenda, Nov. 1997 (Box 38, Folder 48)
    - Board of Trustees Meeting, Dec. 17, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 49)
    - Kendal at Ithaca- Campus Unrest, May 31, 2007 (Box 38, Folder 50)
    - Board Minutes, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Presentation to Board of Trustees at Cornell, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Zoning and Design Subcommittee Minutes, Oct. 20, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Zoning and Design Subcommittee Minutes and Agenda, Sept. 24, 1992 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Other Community Activities
    - Sciencenter (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Sciencenter (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Tompkins County Trust Company: Additional and Renovated Building Space, Phases II and III (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Tompkins County Trust Company, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Tompkins County Trust Company, 1979-1984 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Tompkins County Trust Company, 1984-1992 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Tower Club (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Tower Club Dinner (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Ithaca Tower Club (Box 39, Folder 13)
- Series VIII. Appointment books, diaries, calendars, and notebooks
  - Notebook (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, Oct. 1942-Jan. 1943 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, May 1944-May 1945 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, May 1945-June 1945 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, Oct. 1945 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, Oct. 1945-Nov. 1952 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, Jan. 1952-Apr. 1956 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Notebook, July 1953-Mar. 1958 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Notebook, Apr. 1956Feb. 1959 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1960-July 1962 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1960-Dec. 1962 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Notebook, July 1962-Mar. 1963 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Notebook, Jan. 1963-Mar. 1964 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Notebook, Feb. 1963-Feb. 1967 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Notebook, Mar. 1964-Jan. 1965 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Notebook, Jan. 1965-Feb. 1966 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1965-Dec. 1965 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, Jan. 1966-Dec. 1966 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, Mar. 1966-May 1967 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, June 1966-July 1966 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, May 1967-July 1968 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, June 1968 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, Aug. 1969-July 1969 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, July 1969-June 1970 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, June 1970-Dec. 1971 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, Aug. 1971-Aug. 1981 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, Dec. 1971-Aug. 1973 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, Aug. 1973-Aug. 1974 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1974-Feb. 1976 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, Feb. 1967-July 1977 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, Aug. 1977-Mar. 1982 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, Nov. 1977-Apr. 1979 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1962-1963 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1963-1965 (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1964 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1964-1965 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1965-1966 (Box 40, Folder 21)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1966-1967 (Box 40, Folder 22)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1967-1968 (Box 40, Folder 23)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1968-1969 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1970-1971 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1971-1974 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1974-1976 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1976-1978 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1978-1980 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1980-1981 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1978-1981 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1981-1984 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1984-1987 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1987-1990 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1990-1993 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Calendars and Appointment Books, 1993-1995 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Notebook, Mar. 1982-Dec. 1985 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1982-Apr. 1983 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Notebook, Apr.-Dec. 1983 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Notebook, Dec. 1983-Oct. 1984 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Notebook, Oct.-Sept. 1985 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Notebook, Oct. 1985-Jan. 1986 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Notebook, Mar.-May 1986 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Notebook, Mar. 1986-Mar. 1988 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1987-Nov. 1990 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Notebook, Jan. 1988-Mar. 1989 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Notebook, Oct. 1988-Oct. 1989 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Notebook, May 1989-Sept. 1990 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Notebook, Mar. 1990-Jan. 1992 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Notebook, Sept. 1990-May 1993 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Notebook, Jan. 1992-Mar. 1994 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Notebook, Mar. 1993-Apr. 1994 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Notebook, Nov. 1993-Sept. 1996 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Notebook, July 1991-Nov. 1997 (Box 41, Folder 27)
- Series IX. Personal material
  - College of Engineering - Diploma, 1934 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Promotional Letter, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Cornell Engineer, Oct. 1957 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Honors and Awards, 1957, 1958 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Security Clearances, 1960's (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Employment Contracts, 1969-1976 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Contracts, 1970's (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - VITAE, 1971, 1987, 1993 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - College of Emporia Alumni Activities, 1971-1988 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Columbia University, June 1972 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - University of Kansas - Distinguished Service Citation, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Alumni Organizations, 1972, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Employment Contract, 1975-1977 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Nellie G. Corson - Dedication, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - Corson Tapes, 1977-1994 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Archives, 1976-1996 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Presidential Papers - Kroch Library, 1980's-1990's (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Oral History Interview (Transcript), 1980 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Regarding my Journal (Transcript), 1981 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Corson Building, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - DRC's Vehicle Registration, 1982-1984 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Oral History, 1985 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Berkeley, 1989 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Data, July 1988 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Portrait, 1993 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Cornell University Library Bookplate, 1996 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Boy Scouts - Distinguished Citizen Award, 1997 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Photos (Box 44, Folder 14-17)
  - Contact Sheets - Jon Reis Photography (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Photos (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - "Strategy for a Great Research University: A Symposium Honoring Dale Raymond Corson", Dec. 1999 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - "Strategy for a Great Research University: A Symposium Honoring Dale Raymond Corson" - videotape, Dec. 1999; V-550
- Series X. Photographs and memorabilia
  - Photographs (Box 45)
  - Photographs - Arecibo (Box 45)
  - Christmas Cards Created with Photos taken by Dale (Box 45)
  - Certificates, drawings, and photographs (Box 46)
  - Certificates (Box 48)
  - Medallions (Box 47)
  - Paperweight (Box 47)
  - "College Presidents' Game" (Mapcase-folder 1)
  - Large photo of Corson, Frank Long, and others receiving United States Certificates of Merit. (Mapcase-folder 2)